<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Hungarian Tour Guide</string>
    <!-- First screen. -->
    <string name="greetings">Wellcome to the Hungary!</string>
    <string name="start_button">Start journey</string>
    <!-- Categories -->
    <string name="category_cities">Cities</string>
    <string name="category_parks">National Parks</string>
    <string name="category_spas">Spas</string>
    <string name="category_hungaricums">Hungaricums</string>
    <!-- Cities -->
    <string name="budapest">Budapest</string>
    <string name="budapest_description">Naturally, when you are visiting a foreign a country, seeing the capital is always a must. The city, which is the unification of three (Buda, Pest and Óbuda), is enormously rich in history and culture. One fifth of Hungary\’s population lives here on the banks of River Danube, and several cultures have left their landmarks in the city during the centuries. We could recommend a whole bulk of sights to see, but just to mention a few, one of Europe biggest parliaments, Budavári Palace and Szent István cathedral come to our minds first.</string>
    <string name="gödöllő">Gödöllő</string>
    <string name="gödöllő_description">Elizabeth Wittelsbach, the empress of Austria and the queen of Hungary and Bohemia was one of the most famous monarchs in Europe. She famously loved Hungary, which is proven by the facts that she learned Hungarian and spent most of her time here. Her former palace is still standing in Gödöllő and it can be visited. The building functions mostly as a museum. Whether you intend to visit the palace or not, Gödöllő provides a fascinating sight.</string>
    <string name="vác">Vác</string>
    <string name="vác_description">Vác is a smaller town in the northern region of Hungary. It is situated on the bank of River Danube and provides a quiet asylum from the crowded and noisy city life. It has also won the title of \“the city of culture\” hence its several exhibitions. Just to mention some of its attractions, the Greek Church, the cathedral and the museums are certainly worth a visit. Among the latter ones we would especially recommend Tragor Ignác Museum, where you can visit the local mummies.</string>
    <string name="sopron">Sopron</string>
    <string name="sopron_description">The Civitas Fidelissima or the \“Most Loyal City\” lies near the Austrian border. This geographical situation caused the lots of different cultural impacts that\’s traces can be seen in the city. Besides its famously good beers, Sopron is also popular for being the venue of one of the greatest Hungarian pop music festivals, the Volt Festival.</string>
    <string name="eger">Eger</string>
    <string name="eger_description">Eger is a peaceful historical town in the northeastern part of Hungary. The town about which Géza Gárdonyi wrote his world-famous novel The Stars of Eger is mostly known for its tourist attractions. Here you can find one of the most magnificent castles in Hungary and a spectacular bath. Eger is also a center for Hungarian wine producing\; this is where the famous red wine Egri Bikavér is made.</string>
    <string name="debrecen">Debrecen</string>
    <string name="debrecen_description">Debrecen was the largest city in Hungary until the unification of Budapest in 1873. Every year, on 20th August, the Flower Festival of Debrecen is organized, which is a celebration of art and creativity. The city is also famous for its delicious sausages. Last but not least, Debrecen is one of the greatest centers of musical education in Hungary. Furthermore, it is the most important Calvinist center in Eastern Europe.</string>
    <string name="szentendre">Szentendre</string>
    <string name="szentendre_description">The city of Szentendre is situated only 45 minutes away from Budapest. This close location makes it easier for both tourists from abroad and residents of Budapest to visit this fascinating place. Its most significant attractions are the museums like the MicroArt Museum, the Museum of the Ferenczy Family and the Szamos Marzipan Museum.</string>
    <string name="visegrád">Visegrád</string>
    <string name="visegrád_description">Visegrad — which is the denominator of the V4 alliance — is one of the most spectacular cities with a castle. It resides north to Budapest in about an hour of driving, and its bastions offer a unique view on the area. The local Royal Palace and the Renaissance games are certainly the most characteristic attractions in the city.</string>
    <string name="pécs">Pécs</string>
    <string name="pécs_description">This city on the southwestern edge of the country is filled with history and culture. It was elected as the European Capital of Culture in 2010, and not without a reason. Among the lots of historical and cultural sights to see in Pécs, we would highlight the landmarks of two world religions: the Old Christian Tombs and the Mosque of Pasha Qasim.</string>
    <string name="tokaj">Tokaj</string>
    <string name="tokaj_description">If someone might choose one thing Hungary is famous for, it would probably be the wine. The wine area of Tokaj can be found in the northeastern region of Hungary, and it consists of 30 settlements. Not just the several prize-winning wines are worth a taste, but the sight of the endless vineyards are incomparable with anything else in the world.</string>
    <!-- Spas -->
    <string name="gellert">Gellért Thermal Bath</string>
    <string name="gellert_description">Established during the 15th century, Gellért is characterized by Art Nouveau grandeur and it\’s one of the most stunning baths in the Hungarian capital. During the country\’s Ottoman occupation, Gellért was popular among the Turkish, mostly due to its cavernous spaces and constant supply of geothermally-heated water supply. Gellért boasts several indoor pools and an outdoor wave-pool during the summer months, while guests on its site can sign up for numerous medical treatments.</string>
    <string name="szechenyi"> Széchenyi Thermal Bath</string>
    <string name="szechenyi_description"> Nothing compares to diving into the outdoor pool of amid magical snowfall during the winter months. Budapest\’s largest thermal bath and its alfresco pool is open all year round to provide muscle-melting experience throughout all four seasons. When lounging in the steaming baths outside, you can play chess in the water with the locals, while additional pools, sizzling sauna sessions, and a variety of medical treatments await guests indoors, plus here you can purchase the healing water that is said to have fantastic curing effects on the body.  </string>
    <string name="rudas"> Rudas Thermal Bath</string>
    <string name="rudas_description"> Built during the Ottoman rule in Hungary, Rudas is a state-of-the-art complex, offering a charming locale for swimming and escaping the city\’s bustling scenes. With an old tradition still in place, during the week the bath has separate dates assigned for men and women for using its steaming facilities, while on the weekend Rudas is open for both genders. After a thorough renovation, now this healing heaven boasts modernized facilities, while a panoramic jacuzzi provides sweeping vistas to Pest\’s skyline on the rooftop level. Plus Rudas has a drinking hall to those who want to taste the natural spring water, flowing beneath its ground.</string>
    <string name="lukacs"> Lukács Thermal Bath</string>
    <string name="lukacs_description"> Lukács Thermal Bath was established by the knights of Saint John\’s order, who settled in the area with the aim of curing the sick. Later, orders from Rhodes and Malta took over what\’s known today as Lukács Bath, and established their own monasteries with the same healing purpose, while the building was transformed into a Turkish bath during the Ottoman occupation. In 1999 Lukács was fully revamped, and now the spa features a blend of modern and traditional facilities, including indoor and outdoor pools, alongside a wellness area with sauna, Kneipp pool, a Himalaya salt wall, and much more.</string>
    <string name="kiraly"> Király Thermal Bath</string>
    <string name="kiraly_description"> With a distinct Turkish infusion in its architecture, Király Thermal Bath – once in the possession of the König family – features an eclectic atmosphere of modern and traditional elements. With four pools filled with hot spring water bearing magnesium, calcium, fluoride ions, it\’s a soothing haven, where additional elements, including a jacuzzi, steam cabin, sauna, gym, and various medical treatments ensure complete relaxation.</string>
    <string name="velibej"> Veli Bej Bath</string>
    <string name="velibej_description"> As one of the city\’s lesser-known baths, Veli Bej is a tranquil recreation zone, established during the Ottoman occupation. Its tastefully renovated scenes reserved the place\’s century-old architecture, while the spa\’s internal facilities were upgraded and Veli Bej now boasts a thermal-water pool, infused with calcium carbonate – recommended for those with rheumatic problems or recuperating from surgeries – a jacuzzi, a steam room, and much more.</string>
    <string name="heviz"> Hévíz Spa Lake</string>
    <string name="heviz_description"> Located near Lake Balaton in Western Hungary, Hévíz is the world\’s largest natural thermal lake and offers an unrivaled experience. Used for its thermal properties for over 2,000 years, during the 18th century a spa village began to take shape on its shores, seeing significant expansion in the 1900s. Today, there\’s a bath house on the lake, a hospital offering treatments derived from the thermal waters and a number of accommodation options for visitors hoping to take advantage of the unique healing properties of the spa. Thanks to a combination of the water and the lake bed\’s composition, Hévíz offers benefits such as prevention and treatment of joint disease and post-injury treatment.</string>
    <string name="sarvar"> Sárvár Spa</string>
    <string name="sarvar_description"> Discovered by chance, when engineers drilling for oil came across hot springs instead, since 1961 Sárvár has been home to one of just 10 spas across Europe bestowed with the name ‘Royal Spa\’. Set over an extensive space, there\’s a healing spa, a family spa, an outdoor beach and adventure area open throughout the summer months, as well as a sauna world. Sárvár  benefits from two different types of geothermal water offering various benefits. Originating from a depth of 1,200 metres (3937 ft), the first can get as hot as 43°C (10.4°F) and is commonly used in aiding the healing process after sporting injuries. The second type originates from a depth of 2,000 metres (6561.68 ft) and can reach a pretty scorching 83°C  (181.4°F). Incredibly rich in salt, it\’s useful for dermatological treatments. </string>
    <string name="miskolctapolca"> Miskolctapolca Cave Baths </string>
    <string name="miskolctapolca_description"> Set in a natural cave, the thermal waters in the city of Miskolc first came to prominence during the Ottoman occupation of Hungary. During the 1700s, under the ownership of the Greek Orthodox abbey of Görömböly, the first stages of a bathing complex were set up and three outdoor pools created. By the 1830s the buildings had fallen into disrepair, however from 1837 onward a series of restorations and renovations saw the baths transformed and today, Tapolca enjoys official status as a spa town. The Cave Bath was opened on May 14, 1959 and offers a unique setting in which to enjoy thermal waters with temperatures of approximately 30°C (86°F). </string>
    <string name="egerszalok">Egerszalók Thermal Spa </string>
    <string name="egerszalok_description"> The Eger Thermal Bath, which opened its gates in 1932, is one of the most beautiful and well-known spas of Hungary. The park-bath located in a 5-hectare area is a true paradise for those endeavouring to recover, do sports and have fun. The covered-open water adventure island has 13 pools, sports fields, a playground and direct access to the Turkish Bath. Guests can enjoy the favourable effects of radon curative water and sulphurous thermal water among modern circumstances, all year round. In the northern part of the Thermal Bath, we can find mostly thermal-water, quieter bath functions, while in the southern part, a child-friendly way of bathing inviting younger visitors is located. There are several protected plant species living in the Eger Thermal Bath, among them, the more than 250 year-old oriental sycamore tree, which was voted the Tree of the Year in Hungary in 2012, and in Europe in 2013. </string>
    <!-- National Parks -->
    <string name="hortobagy">Hortobágy National Park</string>
    <string name="hortobagy_description">Located in the eastern part of the country, Hortobágy National Park occupies an area of 800 square km. The protected area was designated as a national park in 1973 and inscribed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1999. It is the country\’s biggest national park. The Hortobágy National Park is noted not only for its natural wealth but also for its rich cultural history. The park\’s notable features are the Nine-holed Bridge, a dark sky preserve, traditional sweep wells, etc. 342 species of birds including migratory species are found in this park.</string>
    <string name="kiskunsag"> Kiskunság National Park</string>
    <string name="kiskunsag_description">Established in 1975, Kiskunság National Park encompasses an area of 570 square km. Also a UNESCO Biosphere Reserve, the national park is located in the Danube–Tisza Interfluve landscape of the country. The national park is unique in that it is not a single territory but comprises of seven distinct units. The Kiskunság National Park features distinct landscapes and biodiversity in different parts through its range. The park is noted for its collection of orchids, marsh tortoises, moving sand dunes, alkali lakes, tourist trails, lookouts, and more. It is often regarded as a birdwatcher\’s paradise due to its rich birdlife. </string>
    <string name="bukk">Bükk National Park </string>
    <string name="bukk_description">Bükk National Park is located in located in northern Hungary\’s Bükk Mountains. The park encompasses an area of 431.3 square km. It is Hungary\’s third oldest park and was established in 1976. The limestone mountains of the park exhibit various karst formations like caves, ravines, and swallow-holes. A 4,000 m long and 245 m deep cave, the Istvánlápa, is located here. Around 90 species of birds nest here. </string>
    <string name="ferto">Fertő-Hanság National Park </string>
    <string name="ferto_description">Located in North-West Hungary, Fertő-Hanság National Park was founded and inaugurated in 1991. The park spans an area of 235.88 square km. The national park attracts a large number of birds due to the presence of the Lake Fertő within its boundaries. This shallow lake provides an ideal habitat for the birds like the common spoonbill, greylag goose, red-breasted goose, etc. The lake also thrives with fish like the northern pike, weatherfish, etc. </string>
    <string name="aggtelek">Aggtelek National Park </string>
    <string name="aggtelek_description">Another magnificent national park of Hungary, the Aggtelek is located in the Aggtelek Karst region in the northern part of the country. The park is well-known for its limestone formations and underground caves. It was established in 1985 and was inscribed as part of World Heritage Site by the UNESCO in 1995. The national park has an area of 198.92 square km and encompasses 280 caves within its boundaries. Europe\’s largest stalactite cave is also a part of this national park. Several species of birds like the eastern imperial eagle, Eurasian bullfinch, red-backed shrike, crested tit, etc., are found here. Mammals like the gray wolf, wild boar, Eurasian lynx, etc., also live in this national park. </string>
    <string name="drava">Danube-Drava National Park </string>
    <string name="drava_description">Established in 1996, this national park is located in the country\’s south-west. It occupies an area of 490 square km including 190 square km of Ramsar wetlands. The national park is rich in bird life with the white-tailed eagle and the black stork having a significant presence at this national park. </string>
    <string name="koros">Körös-Maros National Park</string>
    <string name="koros_description">This Hungarian national park is located in the Southern Great Plain of the country. It was established in 1997 in order to protect the birds of the area. A bustard reserve is also present here. Migratory birds including wild ducks, cranes, plovers, etc., arrive here in large numbers during the autumn season. </string>
    <string name="balaton">Balaton Uplands National Park </string>
    <string name="balaton_description">This national park was established in 1997. It covers an area of 570.190 square km. The national park features varied landscape consisting of hills and mountains, karst formations and flat highlands. This national park was established in 1997. It covers an area of 570.190 square km. The national park features varied landscape consisting of hills and mountains, karst formations and flat highlands. </string>
    <string name="orseg">Őrség National Park </string>
    <string name="orseg_description">One of the ten national parks of Hungary, the Őrség National Park is located in the Vas county of Hungary. The park covers an area of 440 square km. It is the youngest national park in the country and was founded in 2002. </string>
    <string name="ipoly">Danube-Ipoly National Park </string>
    <string name="ipoly_description">This national park hosts a great diversity of species of flora and fauna. It was established in 1997 by including the Börzsöny and Pilis national parks within its boundaries. A section of the River Ipoly\’s floodplain was also added to the territory of the park. </string>
    <!-- Hungaricums -->
    <string name="paprika"> Paprika </string>
    <string name="paprika_description"> Hungary is a major source of high-quality paprika, in grades ranging from sweet (mild, not hot) with a deep bright red colour to rather spicy (hot) with a brownish orange colour. Paprika is used as an ingredient in a wide range of dishes throughout the world. Paprika is an important ingredient of for example soups, such as goulash, and sausages. The two main paprika producing regions are Szeged and Kalocsa.</string>
    <string name="palinka"> Pálinka</string>
    <string name="palinka_description"> Pálinka is the alcoholic drink made only from fruit or pomace grown in side Hungary or some parts in Austria. No additional ingredient accepted by the law except clear water. Real good pálinka is smooth and fruity and the alcohol content is around 40%. There are hundreds of types of Pálinka, depends on the type of fruit. Best distilleries are Agárdi, Gyulai, Zwack, Brill, Márton és lányai, Panyolai, Tarpai, Bestillo. The most known trader is the Rézangyal, they also have several Pálinka pubs.</string>
    <string name="unicum"> Unicum</string>
    <string name="unicum_description"> Unicum is a special, bitter, alcoholic liquer made of herbs and spices that Hungarians swear by as an aid to digestion, among many other things. </string>
    <string name="tokajiaszu"> Tokaji Aszú </string>
    <string name="tokajiaszu_description"> Tokaji is the name of the wines from the historical wine region of Tokaj-Hegyalja in Hungary. The region is noted for its sweet wines made from grapes affected by noble rot. The Tokaji Aszú is world-famous dessert wine of Hungary, aslo called as "king of wines, wine of kings", and really, the greatest kings and queens of Europe ordered this unique drink in the History. The only wine in the world that mentioned in its nation's national anthem.</string>
    <string name="libamaj"> Goose liver or “foie gras” </string>
    <string name="libamaj_description"> Hungary is the world\'s second-largest foie gras "Libamáj" producer and the largest exporter. Goose liver is part of traditional Hungarian cuisine and a must try when visiting the country. The goose liver of Orosháza is a number one gift gourmet tourist take away. A real good goose liver is maybe expensive, but sure an unforgettable experience. </string>
    <string name="szalami"> Pick “Winter” Salami</string>
    <string name="szalami_description"> For more than 130 years the Pick Company has been creating unique flavours and unforgettable treats with its top-quality products. Pick Winter Salami is the company\'s most famous product. This is a real delicacy! Available at any supermarket or grocery store in Hungary.</string>
    <string name="marcipan"> Szamos Marcipán </string>
    <string name="marcipan_description"> The gourmet marzipan/chocolate of Hungary. Szamos Marcipán is a sweet and a very various dessert. The Szamos Marzipan Museum and Confectionery in Szentendre is Hungary\'s first marzipan museum. The exhibition displays the art of marzipan making, including some masterpieces of confectionery, such as the 160 centimetre tall model of the Parliament building. </string>
    <string name="turorudi"> Túró Rudi</string>
    <string name="turorudi_description"> Founded in the 1960\'s by a small group of dairy industry professionals got inspired by a study trip to Moscow and came up with a unique new product - a dark chocolate bar filled with lemony cottage cheese. The \"pöttyös\" (means spotted) theme was part of the marketing campaign, but now it\'s a unique recognizance of this dessert. It has a lot of variants, like large, sweet chololate covered, apricot and strawberry jam filled, and so on, but none of these are as popular as the original one. In foreign countries you may find it under the brand called Dots.</string>
    <string name="porcelan"> Porcelain of Herend</string>
    <string name="porcelan_description"> This Hungarian manufacturing company specializes in luxury hand painted and gilded porcelain. Founded in 1826, it is based in the town of Herend near the city of Veszprém.</string>
    <string name="mangalica"> Mangalica</string>
    <string name="mangalica_description"> Mangalica or Mangalitsa is a breed of pig grown especially in Hungary and the Balkans, known also as a curly-hair hog, which was created in 1833 by the Hungarian Royal Archduke Jozsef. Unlike all popular breeds of hogs, which are meat-type, the Mangalitsa is an extreme lard-type. Meat-type breeds efficiently produce lean meat. Lard-type breeds produce high-quality fat and very marbled, juicy and flavourful meat. Raised properly the mangalica\'s genes allow it to produce some of the world\'s best meat and fat.</string>
    <string name="marha"> Hungarian grey cattle</string>
    <string name="marha_description"> This is an old beef cattle breed from Hungary. Although nowadays Hungarian grey cattle are kept mainly as tourist attractions in the Hortobágy National Park and other Hungarian national parks, these herds also serve as gene banks, due to their reported resistance to cattle diseases which affect more highly bred cattle types.</string>
    <string name="puli"> Puli</string>
    <string name="puli_description"> The Puli is an ancient breed of Hungarian sheep dog. It is medium-sized, sturdy with a unique corded coat. It is a lively, cheerful little dog who is very loyal to his family. Its innate intelligence makes it easy to train but also gives it a mind of its own. The Pulis came to Hungary with the first Hungarian settlers, but at the time of World War II, the breed had almost died out. There was a special breeding program that ensured the survival of these unique little Hungarians.</string>
    <string name="vizsla"> Hungarian Vizsla</string>
    <string name="vizsla_description"> Originating in Hungary, the Hungarian Vizsla was also known as the Hungarian Pointer or the Magyar Pointer. The Vizsla, once established as a breed, was used almost exclusively by nobility for falconing and hunting. The Hungarian Vizsla is a sleek, muscular, medium-sized hunting dog with a beautiful rusty-gold coloured short coat. In Hungarian "Vizsla" means alert and responsive. It is robust but lightly built. In the past few years this breed has become a popular work, show and companion dog. This is an active, energetic working dog with enormous stamina. It is reliable with children and will quickly adapt to family life. The Vizsla is a fine retriever with an excellent nose, and is a good small game and bird hunter and pointer - even on marshy terrain.</string>
    <string name="gulyas"> Goulash </string>
    <string name="gulyas_description"> In the past goulash was made by the shepards of plains. It was a rich and filling food they needed trough a hard day. Real hungarian goulash is made from potato, beef (grey cattle or cow), paprika, spices and sometimes Hungarian gnocchi too. It is made like a soup, but in the end it\'s more like a stew.</string>
    <string name="bikaver"> Bull\'s Blood of Eger </string>
    <string name="bikaver_description"> In Hungarian Egri Bikavér, is a mixed red wine from the Eger Wine Region. According to the legend the name comes from the Turkish Ages, when castle defenders became stronger as they drank red wine, and the turkish soldiers thought the red liquid was bull\'s blood. Now Bikavér is a very popular couvet wine and has it's own festivals and fans.</string>
    <string name="sausages">Sausages</string>
    <string name="sausages_description"> Beside salamis, Hungary has very delicious sausages, quite different from the one you know the popular american style sausages, because these sausages made of pork meat and spiced with paprika. The production procedure is regulated by strict rules. The best two brands of Hungary are the Csabai and Gyulai.</string>
    <string name="cakes"> Hungarian cakes </string>
    <string name="cakes_description"> Somló-style sponge cake (Somlói Galuska) is a popular Hungarian dessert, made of sponge cake, covered with fine chocolate sauce and whipped cream. Dobos cake (Dobostorta) is a layered sponge cake filled with chocolate and nuts, glazed with caramel. Makówki (Mákos Guba) is also a typical Hungarian dessert, made of crescent covered with poppy seed.</string>
    <string name="csipke"> Halasi Lace </string>
    <string name="csipke_description"> Lace of Halas is a 110 years old handicraft Hungaricum. Mostly used as a exclusive decoration of the rooms and halls. Even Pope John Paul II. was gifted with a Halasi Lace while he was in Hungary.</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
</resources>
